The Princess Sapphire
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Princess Knight,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Thirteenth Episode
The Castle of Roses
Today I'm doing nothing
but getting bored!
Prince Sapphire, the
troops are already lined up!
Have you forgotten that at
ten you must review them?
You are already late!
You must fulfill your duty!
Fine behavior!
- Here is a towel for you!
- Hurry up! Make it quick!
Soldiers, attention!
Present arms!
Did you see, Opal? Let's go!
Where are you going, Prince Sapphire?
His Highness is leaving!
Nice move!
We managed to slip away!
Greetings, Your Highness!
Where are you going?
I am by no means obliged
to tell you.
As you wish. I only hope
you don't have in mind...
...to go to the Southern Valley.
- Why can't I go there?
There are often
landslides. It is dangerous.
I'll keep that in mind.
Follow him! And see
if he enters the valley!
I'm going!
Here I am at the crossroads!
Since I love risk, I will go to
the left, into the Southern Valley.
Go, Opal!
So many roses...! Who could
have thrown them on the ground?
It's an interesting place, I don't
see any threat of landslides.
I wonder why Duralumin
wanted to warn me..!
Magnificent, that castle
overlooking the whole valley!
Let's go, Opal!
Oh, no! What are you doing, you idiots?!
Put the tent back up!
Yes, Commander!
Raise the tent!
Thank goodness he had already passed,
otherwise...
How wonderful! Let's go in! Do you want to, Opal?
What's wrong, little horse?
What's the matter? Don't you want to go in?
Easy! Come on, easy!
This is no time to act up!
What is it?
It's only an old castle!
It's nothing special!
Easy! What's wrong, Opal?
- And who are you?
- Your name is Sapphire, right?
Yes, indeed! And I am a Prince!
- You are a real Prince?!
- Yes, exactly!
And tell me, who are you?
Perhaps we will meet again, Prince.
Now please excuse me.
Wait, don't go away!
At least tell me your name!
How strange.
It seemed as if she vanished!
I smell a wonderful scent of roses
No passing!
Who could that be? Better go see!
How did he manage to get in?
Come forward!
I have come to fetch you, Your Highness,
to take you to the castle of the roses.
What a magnificent name for a castle!
I smell again
that strange scent!
The carriage is heading
to the Valley of the South.
I am curious to see
where we will end up.
You may step down, Your
Highness. We have arrived.
It's enchanting!
I'll ask where I am and...
The carriage has disappeared!
How could it have
managed to leave so quickly?
Someone wants me to enter.
What a strange place...
What beautiful statues!
I wonder why those two roses...
And now, how do I get in?
And these other two?
How big they are!
Rather, they look like
rose-shaped boats.
Prince Sapphire!
- Please get onto the boat
of the white rose. - All right.
And what will happen now?
- Welcome, Your Highness.
- Ah, it's you!
I am the Duke of the White Roses.
May I ask you why
you had me come here?
I will explain it to you right away, Prince.
It seems that, centuries ago, my ancestors
built the home you see.
The people of my lineage
have always lived here,
one generation after another.
But for some time now,
someone has been trying...
...to drive me
and my family away.
I beg you, Prince Sapphire,
give us a hand!
Please try to help us!
We do not want to abandon
our ancient home.
Unfortunately, we could not live
anywhere else.
Who could this unworthy person be
who is trying to drive you away?
- It is Grand Duke Duralumin.
- Duralumin?!
Promise me your help!
Come on, take courage!
Damned Grand Duke..!
Alright, I promise you!
Listen, brother: I don't
trust this Prince very much!
You could be
more polite, little brother.
Please, excuse my brother,
the Duke of the Red Roses.
I have thought about our
problem. As for me, I am tired...
...of living in this land, where
nothing but weeds grow!
Therefore I propose to leave
it to Grand Duke Duralumin!
Would you dare betray
the memory of your ancestors..
...and the land that gave you
birth?!
Say what you want,
but I don't care at all!
I have already decided to give
this land to the Grand Duke!
We will go where there
won't be all these weeds...
...and we'll be better off!
- You are a wretch, brother!
Stop fighting!
You are brothers!
Your Highness, you had better not
stick your nose into our business,
or we will spread
your secret around!
My secret?
Brother, it is truly despicable
to reveal other people's secrets!
I don't care! After all, you too
know the Prince's secret!
We have the power to discover
all the secrets of human beings!
What secret are you talking about?
That you are a girl!
Even if you are my brother,
I cannot tolerate...
...that in front of me
anyone behaves like a scoundrel!
On guard!
How dare you?!
Take this!
- Will you stop it?!
- What happened?
Quickly, Prince! Escape!
Hornets, sting Sapphire!
Go away, Prince!
Sting, hornets!
That'll teach you!
- Prince Sapphire!
- Let that be a lesson to him!
I will heal you, Prince.
How strange...!
Perhaps...
Perhaps it was all a dream.
I beg you, try to help us!
But then...!
Magnificent! The range of our
weapons from this fortress is excellent!
If this fortification
is added to the rest,
It will be easy for us
to destroy the neighboring country.
So, finally, we can lay
our hands on this rich territory
...that borders ours!
Prince Sapphire is coming!
What?! Put up the tent!
Put the cannon away!
Hurry up with the operation!
Quick! Operation camouflage!
We mustn't be seen!
Away, quickly!
Move! Out with the cannons!
Close the gun ports!
Hurry up!
I do not like running
on the gun carriage! Stop me!
At your command!
Grand Duke Duralumin!
What are you doing here?
Greetings, Prince! I received word
that there had been a landslide.
It doesn't seem to me that there have been
any landslides.
Tell the truth:
what drove you to come all the way here?
Absolutely nothing special,
Your Highness.
Are you sure? The Duke of the White Roses,
owner of this territory,
told me that you are trying
to take his castle...
...and the annexed Duchy!
- Duke of the White Roses,
his castle..
But what are you talking about, Your Highness?
Don't pretend you know nothing!
Prince, there is no castle
in this valley!
There is only that abandoned castle
on that rocky spur.
Look around: do you see the
castle of this Duke of the Roses?
Perhaps last night
you dreamed it!
Truly strange!
Yet I went inside
Fantastic, Grand Duke!
You always manage to fool him!
Why are you shouting?
They are still working
up there! He will notice!
Idiot!
They are roses! What
are you doing up here?
The weapons for the
fortification, Your Highness.
What?
Is that so? A fortification?
Then Duralumin is preparing an
attack on the neighboring country!
I order you to stop and
not to cut the flowers!
You must not ruin this
country to prepare for war!
I will not allow you to do it!
Sapphire prefers flowers
to war! That damn fool!
The tower is collapsing!
Damn it!
But this is a landslide!
Welcome back among us, Prince.
If you look around,
you will see my companions..
...defeated by the Grand Duke.
By Duralumin?
Why are you pouring water
on their wounds?
Water is the best medicine
What? Water, a medicine?!
My friend! Poor little flower!
I understand! So you are
the spirits of the flowers!
Yes, we are the spirits of the flowers
of the Southern Valley.
I am the spirit
of the white rose.
My followers are weeds.
We have taken on human form
to speak with you.
Thousands of us are trampled
every day by Grand Duke Duralumin,
who has the absurd ambition
to wage war.
Poor flower,
what they have reduced you to!
Rally your friends!
We will defeat Duralumin!
Prince Sapphire! I don't care
if the weeds have to die!
Will you shut up?!
I, spirit of the red rose,
have decided to settle
in Duralumin's abode.
There, I will enjoy the
peace of his sunny garden.
Don't you care about what
will happen to the others?
If the weeds are destroyed, I
will have more land for myself!
Traitor!
And you are a scoundrel!
Hornets, sting Sapphire!
I can't do it!
They are too fast!
I will try to stay still.
But this hornet is huge!
I won't let myself be overwhelmed!
Damn it!
Take this!
And this! And this!
Grab the carriage, Prince!
Quick!
I can't make it!
I've got you! Hold on!
You couldn't make it
with that monstrous hornet!
The hornet keeps following us!
Stay back, you nasty beast! Go away!
Hit it! I order you!
If you come within my reach,
I'll show you!
Open up, Grand Duke Duralumin!
Duke of the Red Roses?!
Welcome, Prince Sapphire!
This boy was telling me something
...very strange.
It is something that concerns you.
So, he was just telling me
that he is willing...
...to testify in public
that you, Prince,
are a girl!
And you can be sure he will do it,
unless...
What are your conditions?
Since I cannot live
any longer,
I would like you to plant
this rose in your garden,
so that my family
can survive.
What the hell kind of proposal is this?!
I'm starting to believe
that you're mocking me!
You don't know who I am! I am
the brother of the King of Silverland,
as well as Minister of Police!
E dovrei piantare nel mio giardino
..questo misero fiore?!
Dove diavolo è sparito
il mio testimone?
Granduca Duralumin,
ora mi spiegherete della fortezza!
Beh, vi dirò, Principe..
Ho costruito quella fortezza
per difendere la nostra terra,
- cioè il vostro regno.
- Otterrò da mio padre...
..il permesso di distruggerla!
Questa terra
non ha bisogno di fortezze!
Mio caro Duca,
almeno voi state bene!
Of course! Why?
What happened to my brother?
I think I understand.
Do not be sad, my dear Duke.
I will destroy that fortress
From now on, you can live
happily in the Southern Valley.
On behalf of my companions,
I thank you, Your Highness.
The flower spirits and I will never
forget your kindness
Goodbye, Sapphire!
Farewell! And be happy!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP